Maximilian Schaum

12529 Schönefeld | +49 162 271 5832 max.schaum4@gmail.com

Resume website: https://max-s-resume.netlify.app/en/

Experienced and reliable Software Engineer. Specialized in **Web Front-End Development with React.js** and a strong background in Back-End. Passionate for creatively delivering solutions to concrete problems with the help of web technologies.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer Front-End

June 2022 – current

eBay, Dreilinden

- Improved customer experience for buying bulky items in a cross-team, cross-border collaborative effort, working on the most important pages in eBay (Checkout and View Item) - React.js, Marko.js, Node.js
- Implemented a new shopping guide experience for costumers to help them find the right product, with a solid 2-5% conversion rate **HTML, CSS, JS**
- Won an internal competition, by making key contributions to a prototype focused on enhancing the trading card collection experience at eBay. I had the honor of pitching the idea to eBay global leadership – React.js, Node.js
- Realized several legally required changes the cancelation process at eBay Plus and extended the cancelation experience to native apps, to prevent them from being kicked off the app store – React.js, Node.js, Scala, Java

Full-Stack Software Engineer | Founder

Mar 2021 – current

Webentwicklung 030 Berlin GmbH, Berlin

- Website design, creation, and SEO optimization React.js
- Implementing interfaces to external job boards for automatic transfer of jobs REST
 ΔΡΙ
- Self-Developed Website Management System for customers React.js, Node.js
- Online analysis tool to automatically test webpages for different quality criteria -React.js, Node.js
- CRM Web-Application for recruiting of personnel **React.js**, **Node.js**
- Chrome Extension to automatically scrape data with direct interface to the CRM Application - REST API

Working Student Front-End Software Engineer

Jun 2020 - Mar 2021

VIPCRUITER GmbH, Berlin

- Webpage maintenance and optimization
- Relaunch of numerous websites from WordPress to Jamstack React.js

Working Student IT / Controlling

Sep 2019 - Jun 2020

Mercedes-Benz AG, Berlin

- Reporting dashboard development
- Excel VBA programming
- Process modeling and automation

Working Student IT

May 2017 - Aug 2019

SCHAUM MASSIVHAUS, Hennigsdorf

- Webpage creation, maintenance, and optimization HTML, CSS, Javascript
- IT administration and accounting

IT-Specialist for software development

Sep 2014 - Apr 2017 IGEPA group GmbH & Co. KG, Berlin

- JD Edwards E1 Database programming
- Java Web application and Interfaces

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) - Mathematics / Computer Science Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin, Berlin	2017 - 2021
Apprenticeship - IT specialist for software development Oberstufenzentrum Informations- und Medizintechnik, Berlin	2014 - 2017

LANGUAGES

Native: German Fluid: English